Javascript Disabled
-------------------

In order to use this site and many of its features, including accessing your profile and giving, javascript must be enabled.

* LOG IN
* MENU

Privacy Policy
==============

**Last modified on January 19, 2023.** 

As noted in the policy below, the English language version of the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use will govern your relationship with Life.Church. You can also use an automatic translation tool like Google Translate to view the documents in your language.

**Important: Please Read**

Life.Church launched in 1996 launch in a two-car garage. Since then, we’ve become recognized for our use of technology to spread the Gospel. We began using video teaching in our services in 2001, were one of the first churches to offer online church in 2006, launched the Bible App in 2008, and more.

Our place at the forefront of digital ministry is driven by our passion to see technology leveraged to help people find hope, peace, and joy in Christ. The Life.Church app and our websites are tools we offer to serve our attenders by connecting them to one another and equipping them to become fully devoted followers of Christ.

Life.Church is also passionate about serving pastors and church leaders around the world to help build the “capital C” Church. Through Life.Church Open Network, leaders can download free resources, and trainings to reach more people.

Every digital product and service we provide is created to help more people pursue a deeper relationship with God safely and securely. We develop these tools as an act of ministry to serve you, and you have choices in your experience. You choose what you access, what you share, and with whom. Your data is yours. Life.Church does not sell your information, nor will we share it with others without your consent.

Every aspect of Life.Church’s digital tools are free, with no strings attached and no advertising. Our intent is to remove every possible barrier so you can know God more.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully because it discusses how we will collect, use, share, and process your personal information. By using Life.Church sites and services, you agree to this Privacy Policy and its terms.

We welcome any questions or comments you may have about this Privacy Policy and our privacy practices. If you have any questions or comments, you may contact us by mail at Life.Church, Attn.: Data Privacy Team, 4600 E. 2nd St., Edmond, Oklahoma 73034, or by email at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church).

The English language version of the Privacy Policy will govern your relationship with Life.Church. Where Life.Church has provided you with a translation other than the English language version of the Privacy Policy, you agree that the translation is provided for your convenience only. If there is any contradiction between what the English language version of the Privacy Policy says and what a translation says, then the English language version takes precedence.

**Table of Contents**

**Definitions:**

To make this document easier to read, we’re going to use some shorthand. For example, when we say “our sites” or “Life.Church sites”—whether we reference them individually or collectively—we’re talking about the websites and applications offered by Life.Church, including, but not limited to: www.life.church, shop.life.church, giving.life.church, and open.life.church, together with their subdomains and content.

These sites are owned and operated by Life.Church Operations, LLC, together with its parents, affiliates, and subsidiaries, which we’ll refer to as “Life.Church,” “us,” or “we” throughout this policy. When we refer to persons interacting with Life.Church in this policy, we’ll use the term “you.”

**Overview:**

By accessing Life.Church sites, you agree to this Privacy Policy and its terms, and you consent to having your data transferred to and processed in the United States. Your use of Life.Church websites and applications may also be governed by Terms of Use. Please read the terms carefully.

This Privacy Policy outlines the types of data we collect from your interactions with Life.Church and how we process that information. You have choices about how your personal information is accessed, collected, shared, and stored by Life.Church. We take the privacy of the information you provide and that we collect seriously, and we implement security safeguards designed to protect your data.

In general, the information we collect depends on the services you request. In addition to personal information that you provide (such as your name, email address, financial information, and other personally identifiable information), we collect Internet and other network activity information with cookies and other automated technologies as discussed below. We use the data we collect and that you provide as well as inferences we make from that information to:

* Provide, support, and personalize our sites and services
* Create, maintain, customize, and secure a Life.Church profile or account
* Process your requests and respond to your inquiries
* Provide information on our products or services
* Maintain the safety, security, and integrity of Life.Church sites and the infrastructure that facilitates use of our sites
* Internal development and analysis of our products and services
* Fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it
* Carry out our obligations and enforce our rights as described in this Privacy Policy in a manner we may describe when you provide the information for another purpose, with your consent.

**How We Collect, Use and Share Your Personal Information**

Below is an overview of the personal information collected on Life.Church sites and the purpose for our collection. Please note: The processing of your information depends on the information you choose to provide and the functionality of our services you choose to use. A more detailed description of our processing of your information is available below.

_Personal Identifiers (name, aliases, Internet Protocol address, email address, address, and similar identifiers)_: Collected to the extent you provide it to us to create an account or for association with your account to ensure proper use and authentication for your account. Your personal information is also used to contact you in connection with your requests and account and as discussed in our Privacy Policy.

_Government Issued Identifications (Social Security numbers, driver’s license number, passport numbers, and similar information)_: Collected and processed to the extent you provide an application for employment or to volunteer to do a background check and otherwise process your application.

_Financial information (credit card information, banking information, and similar information)_: Collected to the extent you provide a donation to or purchase merchandise from us in person. Otherwise, financial information provided to us online is processed by third party service providers as discussed in our Privacy Policy.

_Internet or other network activity (browsing history, search history, information on your interaction with our websites, apps, and other services)_: Collected as you use our sites and services to monitor and ensure the proper operation of our websites, apps, and services; to improve and customize your experience with regard to the same; to improve, modify, and update our services and content generally, and to analyze the same internally; and provide de-identified statistical information to third parties.

_Geolocation data (physical location or movements)_: Collected if you choose to use location-based functionality of our services; however, this information is maintained only on your device and is not stored by Life.Church.

_Professional or employment-related information or non-public educational information_: Collected and processed only to the extent you provide an application for employment or volunteer opportunity to do a background check and otherwise process your application.

_Sensitive Information (religious information, national origin, sexual orientation, race, marital status, health-related information, genetic information, and similar sensitive data)_: Your use of our app or services does not reflect any specific sensitive information, and we do not require that you provide us with the same to use our services. To the extent you choose to provide sensitive information to us through your use of our services, we will process it only with your consent.

_Commercial Information (records concerning your personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies)_: Collected and processed only for purposes of donations and to the extent you provide a donation to or purchase merchandise from us.

_Inferences we make about our users based on data available to us._ Collected as you use our sites and services to improve and customize your experience with regard to our services and to suggest additional functionality and services.

**Your Profile and Information You Provide to Us**

We collect personal data when you provide it to us both offline and online. You do not need to provide personal information to use Life.Church sites. You can create a profile, which allows us to tailor our sites and services to be a more personalized experience. To create a profile, we require your first and last name, an email address, and a password to authenticate you when access your profile. Beyond the personal information needed to create a profile, you have choices about what additional information you provide to us, which may include your zip code, the names of family members, gender, social security number, and your marital status, all of which will be stored in association with your profile. Certain information may be required based on your specific request, such as your social security number for employment inquiries and volunteer requests; we will notify you of this at the time of such a request.

We also collect information about you when you send, receive, or engage in communications with us, including when you submit personal information or requests by emailing help@life.church. We retain those communications to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve our sites and our services.

When you interact with us, the information you provide us is generally stored internally in our third-party relationship management system, or “CRM system.” We will use this information to authenticate you and allow you to access your specific profile, when available. We create user profiles for offline purposes as well, which include volunteerism and inquiries concerning employment. We may combine the information you provide us for your profile and interactions with our sites with information you provide us through other Life.Church sites, services, and products and inferences we make from the same for our internal development to improve the overall quality of our sites, services, and products. We may also make recommendations to you for other Life.Church services based on the information you provide and we infer.

**Your Posts**

Our Life.Church sites have a wide array of functionality, including streaming video, creating prayer requests, and identifying and communicating with your Life.Church groups and teams. Some Life.Church sites may also allow you to publish, distribute, and display content to specific individuals or the public. We will refer to how you provide content and information as “posted” and the content and information posted as “user contributions.” User contributions may be made on public areas of websites and social media accounts you access through our sites or may otherwise be transmitted to third parties. Your user contributions are processed by us to facilitate your ability to create, use, store, and distribute user contributions as you choose. We will associate your user contributions with your account if you opt not to delete them.

If you disclose personal information, whether through collaborative postings, social media, message boards, or otherwise, this information may be collected and used by others. User contributions are posted and transmitted at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users or third parties with whom you choose to share your user contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that unauthorized persons will not view your user contributions, nor do we accept any liability associated with your user contributions.

**Giving**

If you choose to provide a donation through one of the Life.Church sites, then and only then will you be prompted and required to provide credit card, bank account, and other financial information necessary to process the transaction. We will collect the designation for your donation if you provide one, and personal information such as your name, address, phone number, and/or email address to ensure that your donation is used for the purpose you request and to provide you with an annual giving statement that itemizes your donation(s). We will also contact you periodically to inquire if you would like to give to another program, location, or cause. We may contact you through push notification, email, mail, or in-app messages to share these opportunities.

This information, excluding your financial information, is stored in our CRM system. As of the date of this Policy, we use Stripe to process your online donation payments. For information on how third parties process your information, please refer to their privacy policies found here: [https://stripe.com/privacy](https://stripe.com/privacy)

For donations you provide to us in person or by mail, we store your financial information in our databases in an encrypted form for as long as necessary to process your donation and as required by applicable law and GAAP accounting principles.

**Life.Church Merchandise**

For Life.Church sites where you are able to purchase Life.Church-branded clothing and other items, including shop.life.church, your personal and financial information is provided and shared with our third-party contractors that we use to process your order. The third parties are identified at the time of your purchase. For information on how those companies use, store, maintain, and disclose your information, please refer to their respective privacy policies or contact them directly.

**Volunteers and Employment Inquiries**

You may apply to be a volunteer for miscellaneous activities and events in person at a Life.Church location, over the phone, and through one or more of our sites. You may also apply for employment in person and through our sites.

The information we require for volunteer and employment applications are your first and last name, telephone number, address, social security number, date of birth, and, in the case of a job inquiry, your employment history. We will store and use this information to process your application and associate it with your profile if one exists. We will use your social security number and date of birth solely for a background check in connection with your application to be a volunteer and/or employee. We will not share either with any third party except for third-party service providers that enable us to perform background checks and are obligated not to share your information or use it for any other purpose. If you become an employee of Life.Church, your personal information is also used in connection with your employment.

As a ministry volunteer, you may have access to third-party software which allows you to schedule and check in to your volunteer activity, as well as manage other volunteer activity. This location-based information is stored in association with your profile to enable you to see your past volunteerism, and we also use it for our own internal analysis.

**Automatic Data Collection Technologies**

By agreeing to our Privacy Policy, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies as described in this policy. Examples include: web beacons, pixels, tags, and device identifiers we refer to as “cookies.” If you use Life.Church sites without changing your browser or device settings to disable cookies, we assume that you consent to receive all cookies provided through Life.Church sites.

We use cookies to recognize you and/or your device(s) on, off, and across the different applications of our sites and devices. Cookies help to facilitate the best possible user experience for our sites as they allow us to recognize you and maintain your user preferences from session to session, keep your account safe, and improve the functionality of the products and services offered through Life.Church sites. They also help ensure that profile information is used in association with the correct profile. We do not use cookies to facilitate interest-based ads from third parties for third party goods or services.

We log usage data when you use Life.Church sites, including when you view or click on content, browser type, browser language, perform a search or request, the date and time of your request, install an update, seek new functionality, or use one or more tools offered through our sites. We use cookies to identify you and log your use. When you access or leave our sites, we receive the URL of both the site you came from and the one you go to next. We also get information about your IP address, proxy server, operating system, web browser and add-ons, device identifier and features, and/or ISP or your mobile carrier. Using our sites from a mobile device will send us data about your location based on your phone settings and access you have granted the Life.Church sites as discussed below.

We store this information and information about your use of our sites in connection with your profile. We do not share any of your personally identifiable information, device identification, or location without your explicit permission. We advertise on third-party sites such as Facebook and Google and use third-party software development kits (“SDKs”) to attribute a download of a Life.Church application on to the advertisement placed on the third-party site. We do not sell your personal information to any third parties, allow our SDK service providers to sell your personal information to third parties, or use your personal information to solicit the sale of third-party goods or services. We may provide these third parties with aggregate de-identified information concerning ads placed on their sites and downloads that result from those ads.

We use this information to provide a tailored Life.Church site experience for you and to communicate with you more effectively. The information is also collected to determine the aggregate number of unique devices using our sites, track total usage, and analyze usage data to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. We may combine this information with other information to provide you with a better experience and improve the quality of our service. If you do not want us to collect this information, you should cease use of our sites.

We generally maintain the data we collect from cookies for 21 days but may save it for longer when necessary, such as when required by law or for technical reasons. Although most internet browsers accept cookies by default, you can control cookies through your browser settings and similar tools or agree to refuse all cookies altogether. If you refuse to accept cookies, you may prohibit Life.Church from delivering the full capability of our sites, and you may prevent the use of certain features and services that require these technologies.

We cannot regulate other sites, content, or applications of third parties. They may place their cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit personal information from you. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based, targeted content. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about targeted content, contact the responsible provider directly.

**WiFi and GPS**

Some of our sites use GPS or wireless (“WiFi”) information to identify when you are near one of our physical locations. You can provide consent for us to use this information when you first download or begin to use our sites. If you provide consent, we use the information to enable push notifications related to interactions with our Life.Church sites and physical locations.

You also have the ability to manually initiate a location search to identify whether you are at one of our physical locations. When using certain Life.Church sites, you can provide us with your location through your browser, zip code, or city, which a third-party search engine will process. We do not store GPS and WiFi information outside of your device. Once your particular session of use of the feature ends, we will cease to have access to your GPS and WiFi location unless you use the feature again.

After your first use of this functionality and consent for us to use your GPS or WiFi location, we will assume we have consent unless you revoke it through your mobile device’s settings.

**Life.Church Content**

We collect how you use the content available through our sites and the language you choose to utilize that content. We process this information to allow you to access and use content through each session of your use of our sites. You can choose whether to download certain Life.Church content to your device. You will have the option to allow Life.Church access to your device’s storage to add and modify this downloaded content. Access to the storage of your device is only used by Life.Church for downloading this requested content to your device.

It is your choice whether to create, access, or store Life.Church information and content. If you do, we will store it in association with your profile. We may use information about your use of Life.Church and the inferences we make from that use to provide recommendations to you of other Life.Church content. You may opt out of receiving these recommendations by email, as discussed below.

**Communication From Us to You**

We communicate with you through push notification, email, or in-app messages. If we communicate to you through email, you may unsubscribe to these messages via the unsubscribe link in the emails providing these messages. You can update your push notification settings at any time within the settings menu of the Life.Church App.

We may also communicate with you via text message, and you consent to us sending you texts when you create an account in one of our Life.Church sites. We may text you about things like events, new content, and requests for volunteer or donation support. The frequency of these messages may vary, and message and data rates may apply. Some of the text messages we send may include links to websites, which will require a web browser and internet access. You may text STOP to opt out or HELP for help at any time to 82686 or 405-939-1120 or email us at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church "mailto:dataprivacy@life.church"). Certain carriers may not be liable for delayed or undeliverable messages.

**Recommendations and General Information**

We use the data about you and inferences we make from that data to recommend certain content and functionality as well as additional products and services offered by Life.Church.

We may combine the information you provide with information we collect and the inferences we make for our internal development to improve the overall quality of all services and products provided by Life.Church.

We may make recommendations to you for other Life.Church services and products based on the information you provide, and we infer.

We may also use the data we have about you and inferences we make from that data to contact you regarding other opportunities to engage with Life.Church.

We may contact you through push notification, email, mail, or in-app messages to discuss these recommendations and opportunities, how to use our sites, and other news.

**Security, Legal, and Technical Issues**

We may use your information to contact you about account security, legal, and other service-related issues. Please be aware that you cannot opt out of receiving such messages from us. We may use your personal information to investigate, respond to, and resolve legal, security, and technical issues and complaints, including, as necessary, security purposes or possible fraud, violations of law or our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, or attempts to harm; however, you agree that we have no obligation to prevent or monitor for any of the preceding.

**Notice**

We may use your personal information to provide notice regarding a security incident or data breach by:

* sending a message to the email address you provide, as applicable
* posting to a publicly facing page of Life.Church sites or through an in-app messages
* sharing notices through major statewide media and/or telephonic means, including calls and/or text messages, even if sent via automated means including automated dialers.

Standard text and data messaging rates may apply from your carrier.

Notices sent by email will be effective when we send the email. Notices we provide by posting will be effective upon posting and by in-app messaging when the message is made. Notices we provide through telephonic means will be effective when transmitted or dialed. You consent to receiving electronic communications from Life.Church relating to your use and access of the services provided by Life.Church. It is your responsibility to keep your email address and any other contact information you provide to us current so that we may provide these communications to you.

**Analytics and Performance**

We internally analyze the personal data available to us, the use of content found on our sites, and the inferences we make from that data to provide and update Life.Church sites, communicate with you, and process information as discussed in this Policy, and for internal analytics such as to observe social, economic, and geographic trends as they pertain to Life.Church content.

In some cases, we work with trusted third parties to perform this research under controls that are designed to protect your privacy as outlined below. For example, we may use your data to generate statistics about overall usage of one of our sites worldwide, in specific geographic regions, or at specific events or locations.

We also use de-identified and aggregate user data to market our sites, including communications that promote growth. Where we publicly share stats of our growth, we analyze and publish the data in an aggregated form, protecting your privacy and keeping your identity and personal information confidential. We use data, including user-provided personal information, aggregations of user data collected through the use of our sites, public feedback, and information inferred from this data to conduct internal research and development in order to provide a better overall experience on Life.Church sites, measure the performance of our sites and increase use of our sites and their features. This is done by making changes to Life.Church sites that are generally available and by sending messages suggesting functionality and content.

**Sensitive Data**

By using Life.Church application and sites, we do not assume that you are of any particular religious affiliation or are expressing to us any particular religious belief. We assume you are interested in the content we provide. We do not require users to provide information about such beliefs or any other sensitive data such as race, ethnicity, philosophical beliefs, or physical or mental health to use Life.Church sites or create or maintain a Life.Church profile.

Some features available through Life.Church sites utilize personal information that may reflect your religious or philosophical beliefs, but you are not required to provide such information. In addition to these features, you have control over the content of certain things you create, share, and store through Life.Church, and if you provide us with sensitive information with any content you create, share, and store, we will assume we have your consent to process that information.

We will not sell your sensitive personal information, but we may need to share it with third-party service providers that enable us to provide the Life.Church sites and/or certain app features and those service providers are required to keep your personal information confidential and only use it to provide us with their services. We will process the sensitive information we collect and inferences we make about the same in accordance with our Privacy Policy and for the purpose of allowing and facilitating your use of those specific app features, to personalize your user experience, suggest other content and services, and internally improve our services.

If you choose to provide any sensitive information to us, we may use that information with other non-sensitive information you provide to create a more personalized Life.Church experience for you and to perform the services and actions you request, such as sharing or storing content you create. In any event, Life.Church will only process sensitive data you provide to us for Life.Church’s legitimate activities on your behalf and solely in accordance with the terms of this policy and any additional requests you make about the information. We will also maintain your information subject to appropriate safeguards discussed in this policy and otherwise provided by Life.Church.

You have the right to withdraw your consent to our collection and processing of your sensitive personal information by turning off and ceasing to use Life.Church features that use this information, or by contacting us via mail at Life.Church, Attn.: Data Privacy Team, 4600 E. 2nd St., Edmond, Oklahoma 73034, or by email at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church). Withdrawing your consent may hinder our ability to provide certain functionality.

**Disclosure of Your Information**

We do not sell or share your personal data with any third-party advertisers or ad networks for their advertising purposes. We may disclose your personal information to third parties to process information as described above and otherwise enable our ability to provide Life.Church, as further discussed below.

**Disclosure on Your Behalf**

We may disclose personal information that we collect, or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy to fulfill our obligations, the purpose for which you provide it, a purpose you request when you provide the information, or any other purpose for which we have your consent.

**Disclosure by You**

If and when you share information through our sites, it is viewable by you and anyone else you choose to share it with. If you give access to your account to other applications and services, based on your approval, those services would have access to your shared information. The use, collection, and protection of your data by such third-party services are subject to those third parties’ policies.

**Internal Disclosure**

We will share your personal data internally within Life.Church and its affiliates to help combine the personal information covered across the different aspects of Life.Church sites and our other products and services to help provide services to you in a manner that is personalized and useful to you and others. For example, we can personalize potential services to recommend to you using cookies or similar technologies that track what functionality you have already opted to receive.

**Service Providers**

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy to contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use solely to support our sites (such as cloud hosting, cookie providers maintenance, analysis, audit, external marketing, payments, fraud detection, communication, and development), as well as to support our operations (such as communicating with you for potential employment purposes). We may combine the information we have with the information of these service providers to facilitate their support. For example, some of the platforms used to send emails and notifications provided through Life.Church are built and managed by third parties, so some of your information is sent securely to those services to provide such functionality. They will have access to your information as reasonably necessary to perform tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose it to others or use it for other purposes. We may also provide aggregate, de-identified information concerning the use of Life.Church sites with third parties.

**Content Providers**

We utilize certain third parties to provide content on our sites. We do not share the personal information of users with these third parties. We may provide these third parties with aggregate analytics concerning the use of their content using de-identified and anonymized data.

**Legal Process and Subpoena**

We may need to disclose information about you when required by law, subpoena, or other legal process. We attempt to notify users about legal demands for their personal data when appropriate in our judgment, unless prohibited by law or court order or when the request is an emergency. We may dispute such demands when we believe, in our discretion, that the requests are overbroad, vague, or lack proper authority, but we do not promise to challenge every demand. We may also need to disclose your information if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to:

* Investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies;
* Enforce our agreements with you;
* Investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations;
* Protect the security or integrity of our sites or
* Exercise or protect the rights and safety of Life.Church, our users, personnel, you, or others. 

We also reserve the right to confidentially disclose personal information we have about you in connection with a potential or actual merger or acquisition such as the sale of all or substantially all our assets.

**Deleting, Accessing, and Correcting Your Information**

**How to Make Your Requests**

For personal data that we have about you, you may request the following:

**Deletion:** You may ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data. Please note that doing so may limit your ability to use certain functionality of Life.Church sites. Please note that an email address is required to have an account to ensure we can properly authenticate potential users of that account.

**Correction/Modification**: You may edit some of your personal data through your account or ask us to change, update, or fix your data in certain cases, including if it is inaccurate.

**Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data**: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data or to limit our use of it.

**Right to Access and/or Take Your Data**: You can ask us for a copy of or disclosure concerning your personal data you provided to us.

Certain laws may provide the right to make additional requests concerning your personal information. If you have provided us with personal information and wish to make such a request under a specific region’s law, include the phrase “\[Your State/Country\] Privacy Request” in the subject line of your request and send your request via email to [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church) or via mail to Life.Church, attn.: Data Privacy Team, 4600 E. 2nd St., Edmond, Oklahoma 73034.

We ask that individuals making requests identify themselves with at least their name, mailing address, and email address and identify the information requested to be accessed, corrected, or removed before we process the request. We may seek additional information to verify a requestor’s identity. We may decline to process requests if we cannot verify the requestor's identity or if we believe the request will jeopardize the privacy of others, violate any law or legal requirement, cause the information to be incorrect, or for a similar legitimate purpose.

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under applicable law. We do not charge a fee to process or respond to a verifiable request concerning your personal information unless it is excessive, unduly burdensome, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide a cost estimate before completing your request.

**Deleting Your Account**

You can delete your Life.Church account credentials at any time using the settings function in the Life.Church application. To request deletion of all account data, you must follow the deletion request instructions above; however, when you delete your account, we will delete the information associated with your account, such as user contributions you have created, received, or shared. If you do not want to delete your account or this information but want to temporarily stop using a Life.Church site, you may cease use, and we will maintain your account and the information associated with your account until you resume use or delete your account, whichever comes first.

We generally retain and process information and user contributions associated with your account until your account is deleted. You can manage, change, and delete certain information associated with your account using the Life.Church application or online at www.life.church/profile or by limiting specific app features. If you’d like us to delete your account and all the information associated with your account, you may contact us at the mailing address or email address set forth above.

If you choose to delete your account or ask that we modify or delete personal information, we will delete and purge personal information we have stored about you in a way that is electronically irreversible; however, we may retain your personal data if we have a legal right or obligation to maintain the information or to meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, maintain security, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our rights, or fulfill any other requests from you (for example, to opt-out of further messages or for a copy of your data). Otherwise, if you request that we delete your account, we will delete your account and all the information we have that is associated with your account, except for aggregated statistics based on de-identified information and inferences we have made (for example, the fact that you downloaded our application, without identifying you or maintaining personal information associated with that account).

Our deletion of your information and account will generally take up to 45 days from your request; however, cached information may take up to 30 days to delete. Please note that we have no control of the information you have shared with others through our sites and applications after you close your account, ask to delete information, or attempt to delete your account yourself. Your information and content you have shared may continue to be displayed in the services of others, including search engine results, until their cache refreshes.

**Security and Protection**

We implement security safeguards designed to protect your data. These include using encryption for your data while being transmitted between your device or browser and our servers and while at rest. Data provided to us through our sites is also stored in an ISO 27017-certified infrastructure management system, meaning it has been audited and found in compliance with the requirements of the management system standards ISO 27017, an internationally recognized code of practice for information security controls for cloud services. However, given the nature of communications and information technology and that the use of the internet has inherent risks, although we regularly monitor for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, we cannot warrant or guarantee that information provided to us through our sites or stored in our systems or otherwise will be free from unauthorized intrusion by others, nor can we warrant or guarantee that such data may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

**Life.Church Online**

Life.Church allows users to access its services through the Life.Church Online platform. Where you use Life.Church Online, we collect your first name, last name, nick name, email and phone number to create your Life.Church Online account. We also collect your age, gender, time zone, date of birth, and city and state where you provide it.

Where you create a Life.Church Online profile, the automatic data collection technologies referenced above are used to log your IP address and phone carrier to help associate your uses of your Life.Church Online account from session to session and to better facilitate Life.Church Online chat communications. In addition to the content and posts noted above, Life.Church Online allows users to chat with other users and create other shareable posts, such as emojis and reactions to certain content, where you “raise your hand” in Life.Church Online, and what content you choose to stream and access when using this site. We store this information in association with your Life.Church Online account for so long as you do not delete the content.

**Children**

We do not collect personal information from any person we know is under 18 without the consent of that minor’s parent or legal guardian.

A parent or guardian may consent to using our sites or services by a minor. However, we ask that you discuss the risks of sharing personal information on the Internet with your children and require that they refrain from communicating with any third parties or sharing any personal information online or otherwise without the supervision of a parent or guardian. Should you allow your minor child to use our sites or services, you are solely responsible for supervising the minor’s use of the same and assume full responsibility for the processing of any information provided to us by that minor.

Where you associate your minor child’s information with your account, we will assume you consent to our processing of that information in accordance with this policy and other privacy notices and terms we may provide to you from time to time. If you allow your minor child to use our sites, we ask that you discuss the risks of sharing personal information on the Internet with your children and require that they refrain from communicating with any third parties or sharing any personal information with other users. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 18, please contact us at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church).

**Processing of Data**

We will only collect and process personal data about you where we have lawful bases. Lawful bases include consent where you given it, contracts, and other legitimate interests. Such legitimate interests include protection to you, us, other users, and third parties, to comply with applicable law, to enable and administer our internal processes, to manage corporate transactions, to generally understand and improve our internal processes and user experience, and to enable us and other users of our sites to connect with you to exchange information, provided that the preceding adequately protects your rights and freedoms. Where we rely on your consent to process personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time, and where we rely on legitimate interests, you have the right to object. If you have any questions about the lawful bases upon which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church).

**Third Party Information Collection**

This Privacy Policy applies only to sites and apps owned and operated by Life.Church. Our sites may contain links to other websites or apps. You are responsible for reviewing the privacy statements and policies of those other websites you choose to link to or from one of our sites so that you can understand how those websites collect, use, and store your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements, policies or content of other websites or apps, including websites you link to or from a Life.Church site. Websites containing co-branding (referencing our name and a third party’s name) contain content delivered by the third party, not us.

If you link to other websites, applications, and services or profiles you have with third-party applications, you will provide the personal data stored on those applications to Life.Church. For example, you may link your Facebook account to your profile, providing personal information you have opted to share through Facebook to Life.Church. When you do so, we are provided with your Facebook or other applicable social media username. You may revoke the link with such accounts and third-party applications by modifying your settings with those applications. As noted above, third-party sites that link to or are associated with our sites may collect information using automated technologies such as cookies. We have no control over such collection and use, which are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties.

**Users Outside the United States**

We are based in Oklahoma within the United States, and the laws of the U.S. and the State of Oklahoma govern your use of our sites and this Privacy Policy. If you are using one of our sites from outside this state or country, your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the U.S. where our servers are located, and our central database is operated. We process data both inside and outside of the U.S. and rely on contractual commitments between us and companies transferring personal data that require the protection and security of such data for your privacy. The data protection and other laws of the State of Oklahoma, the U.S., and other countries might not be as comprehensive and may differ from those in your state or country. By using a Life.Church site, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it, as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy ocassionally to reflect changes in our practices. Life.Church is consistently seeks new and improved ways to offer our sites and increase engagement. As we improve our sites, this may also mean the collection of new data or new ways to use data. Because our sites are dynamic, and we continuously seek to offer new features, we may require changes in our collection or processing of information. If we collect materially different personal data or materially change how we use your data, we will update this Privacy Policy.

We will post any changes to our Privacy Policy on this page. If we make material changes to how we process our users’ personal information, we will provide a notice that the Privacy Policy has been updated. The date the Privacy Policy was last modified is identified at the beginning of the Policy. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date, active, and deliverable email address for you and for periodically visiting this Privacy Policy to check for any changes.

**Archived Versions**

**Contact Information**

To ask questions or comment about this Privacy Policy and our privacy practices, you may contact us at: Life.Church, Inc., Attn.: Data Privacy, 4600 E. 2nd St., Edmond, Oklahoma 73034, or at [dataprivacy@life.church](mailto:dataprivacy@life.church).

Attend [Life.Church Online](https://live.life.church/) or a [Life.Church location](https://www.life.church/locations/).

[Privacy Policy](https://www.life.church/privacy/) | [Terms of Use](https://www.life.church/terms/) | [Vulnerability Disclosure Program](https://www.life.church/vulnerability-disclosure-program/) {{consent\_manager}}

© 2024 Life.Church. All rights reserved.
